SIBONELO MBATHA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Durban South Africa

PHONE

0799284812

EMAIL

sibzmbatha870@gmail.com

LINKS

Web Portfolio

SKILLS

JavaScript

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

React

• • • • 0

HTML & CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Database Management

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

C#

.

JIRA

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Git

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Adobe XD

• • • 0 0

SQL

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Java

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

React Native

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

LANGUAGES

English

• • • •

PROFILE

Experienced Junior Software Developer, specializing in web and mobile development. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, deployment, documentation and debugging processes. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including JavaScript, ASP.NET, C#, HTML & CSS, GIT, and SQL. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, communicate and work with clients as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Junior Software Developer, ComputASSIST

Durban

Mar 2021 — Present

Working mainly on web and mobile based solutions where I have been given the responsibility of working on the full project life cycle. My responsibilities include the following.

- Conversion of legacy systems to web and mobile based platforms using both React and React Native libraries
- Creation of new web based systems comprising of both React front-end and C# back-end built from the ground up
- · Documentation of all managed systems
- · Project management using Jira
- · Creation of UI Design using Adobe XD
- · Creation of system workflows and components using Draw.io
- · Debugging and system testing
- · Tutorial videos and Training on all managed systems
- · Deployment on both mobile and web based solutions
- Integration with existing systems between other departments using languages such as Visual Basic and Delphi
- · Maintenance of managed systems and the App Store for mobile apps

Internship, Xact ERP

Durban

Nov 2019 — Dec 2019

Worked in their development programmer where as interns we were equipped with key skills to prepare us for the working environment, where our responsibilities included the following.

- Developing new and modern designs for their existing systems to improve user experience
- · Creating various database schemas
- · CRUD and SQL queries for newly developed features
- $\cdot\;$ SCRUM project management and weekly catch up meetings

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer and Information Sciences in Application Development, Varsity College Westville

Durban

Jan 2018 — Nov 2020

• • • •

The IIE Bachelor of Computer and Information Sciences in Application
Development provides candidates with a thorough theoretical grounding and
knowledge base in the key principles of information technology (IT), programming,
mobile application development across platforms, web development, database
design, troubleshooting, testing, connectivity, customisation and project
management.

Higher Certificate in IT and Support Services, Varsity College Westvilee

Durban

Jan 2017 — Dec 2017

 Technical assistance and computer-related support in the business environment. Subjects focus on end-user computing, help desk support, basic web development, as well as business practice and communication.

A+ in IT Principles, Damelin

Durban

Jan 2016 — Dec 2016

· Certification for technical support and IT operational roles.

St Benedict High School

Durban

Jan 2011 — Nov 2015

· Matriculated with a Bachelors Degree

STRENGTHS

- · Communication Skills
- · Time management
- · Team work
- · Able to work on individual projects
- · Being able to manage a team
- Project management

REFERENCES

Shayne Cairns from ComputAssist

shayne.cairns@order-direct.co.za

Derek Bestel from Xact ERP

derekb@xacterp.co.za